Nickson Kaigi

Software Engineer

Email: nickaigi@gmail.com Mobile: +254 724 708 852

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/nickson-kaigi GitHub: github.com/nickaigi

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineer, with over a decade of experience working with Python and Agile Software Development Practices. Driven individual, with a background in Computer Science and vast experience in Software Development, Engineering Design and Open Source Software solutions in developing and shipping software and data products.

EXPERIENCE

SKUify Limited

United Kingdom - Remote

Full Stack Engineer

December 2023 - December 2024

- Contributed to the successful development of the SKUify SaaS, enhancing inventory management and pricing optimization for Amazon and Arbitrage sellers, resulting in improved user engagement and operational efficiency.
- Successfully migrated big tables used by the project to PostgreSQL partitioned tables, resulting in quicker query execution and improving API load times.
- Maintained CI/CD pipelines in Jenkins for routine deployment to our test and production servers, ensuring smooth operations and monitoring of projects.
- Led the development of seller dashboards by fetching reports generated by Amazon SP-API (Selling Partner API) that is a REST based API.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, Django REST Framework, React, PostgreSQL, Celery, Jenkins, Amazon SP-API

FreeCast Inc

United States of America - Remote

Back-end Engineer

September 2022 - November 2023

- Played a role in the transition of the FreeCast APIs from Django REST Framework to FastAPI, increasing the number of Requests per Second (RPS) that the project could handle.
- Actively participated in collaborating with cross-functional teams to ensure alignment with Agile methodologies.

Project Tech Stack: Python, FastAPI, Django, Django REST Framework, MySQL, Docker, GitHub Actions

Sum Software Limited

United Kingdom - Remote

Full Stack Engineer

November 2021 - July 2022

- Built the "Journey" component of the Sumfully SaaS, streamlining inventory management for Amazon and Arbitrage sellers, incorporating feedback from stakeholders to align with the evolving software development practices.
- Developed custom Python scripts that generated report data from Amaon Marketplace Web Service (MWS) that was SOAP based API.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, Django REST Framework, React, PostgreSQL, Celery, Jenkins

World Bank Group

United States of America - Remote

Technical Consultant

December 2021 - January 2022

• Led the development of the Personal Case Based Teaching (PCBT) prototype that aimed to analyze past judgments in courts of law in a bid to determine judgmental bias. This project involved the use of monitoring tools to track performance and operations.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, Django REST Framework, React, PostgreSQL, Celery, Jenkins

Maxum Data Limited

New Zealand - Remote

Lead Developer

June 2015 - October 2021

- Developed the mPort project that tracked mobile phone number portability across mobile network operators in New Zealand, resulting in seamless mobile network operator migration.
- Developed a search tool for custom Toll Free numbers that lead to an increase in toll free number uptake from users.
- Wrote Lua scripts that allowed customization of Freeswitch, simplifying customization tasks for the network operation team

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, MySQL, Lua,

Domains Bot Italy - Remote

Senior Python Engineer

June 2015 - September 2015

• Played a key role in the database redesign and upgrade on the Domains Bot project that resulted in faster database queries and shorter API response times.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, MySQL

SunUp Financial LLC

United States - Remote

Senior Python Engineer

May 2014 - January 2015

• Worked on the development of the "Balance Credit" web project that created the onboarding process for customers of the Company's Pay Day loans product, emphasizing with the design team to enhance user experience.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, MySQL, JQuery

Soko Inc. Nairobi, Kenya

Senior Python Engineer

July 2013 - April 2014

- Led the development of a Android mobile app for Soko Artisans.
- Participated in REST API development on the project that were used on by the Android app.
- Worked on the transition of the Soko web project from Django Framework to the Pyramid Web Framework.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, Django REST Framework, Pyramid Framework, MySQL, Android.

Sweet Relish LLC USA, Remote

Senior Python Engineer

December 2012 - July 2013

- Worked on the Sweet Relish mobile website that was based on JQuery mobile.
- Contributed bug fixes on the project, enhancing overall application performance.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, MySQL

Code Painters LLC

USA, Remote

Lead Engineer

September 2012 - November 2012

• Led the development Gym management website that included subscription management and gym session reservation.

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, MySQL, JQuery

Apartment Rentals

USA, Remote

Python Engineer

April 2012

• Worked on bug fixes to the project

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, MySQL, JQuery

MANteresting

USA, Remote

Django Developer

March 2012 - April 2012

- Led the development of version 1 of MANteresting REST APIs that were used on the mobile version of the project, ensuring adherence to Agile methods.
- Worked on bug fixes

Project Tech Stack: Python, Django, REST API, MySQL, JQuery

Alliance Technologies Limited

Nairobi, Kenya

Software Engineer - Intern

September 2011 - December 2011

Developed a mobile version proof of concept for the A1 ERP.

Project Tech Stack: Java, J2ME, PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology | Bsc. Computer Science 2012

- Second Class Honors, Upper Division
- Coursework: Computer Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Management, Computer Security

CERTIFICATION & AWARDS

Kotlin for Java Developers, Coursera.

2019

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Technical Python, Django, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React Js, Next Js, Linux, Open Source Software.

Interests Chess